There are two different ways that you can write your composables and this is this is just a JavaScript thing
But I want to be explicit about it because it's an easily overlooked thing if you're newer to JavaScript
And that you can do named exports versus default exports, and so what do I mean by that?
So you might have noticed in my use task composable. I explicitly export every single thing that's in here
And this is what they call a named export and the reason for that is because you're being you're basically naming every single export that you expect to
Export out of your composable. The alternative here is you could do something like this. You can do export default and there's like a function and then the function then returns
Okay, so this is how this will look
Don't export
down export and then return filter tasks and format task that's label
Okay, so in this one you'll notice rather than explicitly exporting constants or explicit functions
I just have this unnamed function that's being exported with this keyword default the difference is
When you're importing it, you'll notice first of all this is broken now and it's because by using the default what you're doing is you're saying this file contains this blob of a function and you can call it whatever
So in this case, I'm just going to be consistent though. I'm going to call it used task and then I'm going to import it from composable slash use I think that's what I did yes
And then what happens is use task is a function that then exposes the stuff inside
Okay, so why does this matter why we talking about this? Well, one because the two offering formats do show up and I want people to be able to make explicit choices behind what they're doing
And so if I could make a case to you as to which one I would recommend is I would actually recommend the named one over the default export
And the reason for that is because the default export has this
Blubbiness about it that basically says you can name it whatever you want so I might name it use task someone else might come along and just say task feature
There's nothing stopping anyone from doing differently because it's you're naming the blob that's coming back to you from your default export because what it it's it's unnamed to begin with
But if we go back to the original actually let me do this let me do do do let me comment this out and then take these two again
All right, so then what we'll say here is
Is
The export them explicitly filter tasks and export the format status label explicitly and then I'll make a note here
This is called a default export example
What you what I love about this is that once you have your composable like you've had your import
Oh wait, did you something wrong you said it you're stuff is basically the autocomplete is there for you
And so there's no one ever deciding like oh actually I'm going to name it something differently and then so you might think okay well then name collision right like what if someone else has something called filter tasks
Well, that's totally fine. You just name it something different you filter tasks
Wait
As new filter has sorry forgot that's syntax so then now you can use new filter task
And so to me the named
The named export provide consistency get your autocomplete and you don't get naming collisions and so it does seem to carry kind of all the benefits that you expect
Now granted we will learn about functions inside of our composables later, but this is kind of like the foray into it all